professor for beer are you ready for
another exciting lesson we are going to
be talking about algebra and I have
several books with valuable information
to share oh no my algebra books are
missing some scoundrel is trying to
prevent me from teaching you algebra
there are only five books yes five on my
shelf the total number of books on my
shelf should equal 14 where are my
missing books and how many are missing
wait a minute this could be written as a
math problem as I said before I never
repeat myself so pay attention yes this
looks like a math problem to me an
equation to be exact the equal sign
gives it away when you have a
mathematical sentence with an equal sign
you are dealing with an equation but
what does this mean missing algebra
books well that is a mysterious number
that is unknown when you have an unknown
number you can use a letter or a symbol
to represent it in an equation this is
known as a variable let's use the letter
X Y okay let's use the letter Y 5 plus y
equals 14 oh you meant why not why well
you can also use Y or any other letter
or symbol to stand for an unknown number
it makes our mathematical sentence
easier to work with let's go ahead and
stick with X X is the most commonly used
variable and whose idea was that
a clever expert now that you have an
equation it is your job to solve it by
finding what the variable X stands for
you want your equation to look like this
x equals something now now it isn't that
hard just follow this one very important
rule equations like everything to be
fair nickel so here's a very important
rule whatever you do to one side you
must do to the other take 5 away from
this side that is a good way of getting
rid of the 5 because 5 take away 5 is 0
but we
member are very important rule what you
do to one side he must do to the other
so take away five from this side do now
that the five is gone from this side X
is by itself and x equals nine notice
how I lined up the e cosine as I figured
out this equation we can check our
answer by plugging nine back into our
original equation in place of the X 5
plus nine equals 14 correct what about
this equation X minus 21 equals eight
again you want to get the unknown X all
by itself how can you make minus 21 + 2
a 0 let's add 21 to both sides minus 21
plus 21 equals 0 and a 2 plus 21 equals
29 so x equals 29 there you have it you
have learned about mathematical
equations using variables come to think
of it you have just learned algebra we
did not need my missing algebra books
after all oh wait a minute I was sitting
on them I had them all along you could
say that my algebra books are my seat of
learning
I like algebra and I never got a bad
grade in algebra but then I never took
out the bra just learned it on my own
oh well until next time be sure to learn
new information daily be sure to share
and subscribe for more videos that make
learning fun
[Music]
[Applause]